<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Madison Brenner Portfolio</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Madison Brenner Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Python with R</title>
      <link>/blog/python/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/python/</guid>
      <description>The only system I have used throughout my undergraduate degree has been R Studio, so I have become pretty confident in my skills using it. However, Python is a whole different story. I had never before printed “hello world” before one of the last lectures of Compuational Biology. I quickly learned though that R Studio and Python can go hand in hand as follows.
You can save variables using Python chunks:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: Gun Violence Incidents in the United States in 2014 - Madison Brenner</title>
      <link>/project2madisonbrenner/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project2madisonbrenner/</guid>
      <description>The data chosen for this project was a large dataset compiling every gun violence indident and the number of people injured or killed in each incident. This was merged with a dataset that showed each possible gun law a state did and did not have, and this was merged with the first dataset to only display gun law and violence incidents from the entire year of 2014. The dataset contains many variables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Election Data by State for the 2016 Presidential Elections</title>
      <link>/prez_project_meb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/prez_project_meb/</guid>
      <description>Madison Brenner mb57363
The following data sets are titled ‘Election16’ ‘RaceData16’ and were pulled from https://vincentarelbundock.github.io/Rdatasets/datasets.html and the U.S. Census website. These two datasets together compile statistics on the demographics of voters by state in the 2016 presidential election. Election16 datasets contain the fifty states, the abbreviation for each state, the per capita income by state, the percent of high school graduates, percent of college graduates, percent of individuals with advanced degrees, the difference between republican and democrat percentages by state, and finally the winner of the election.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects Here are some projects I have recently completed:
  Election Data by State for the 2016 Presidential Elections
  Gun Violence Incidents in the United States in 2014
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project</title>
      <link>/project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/</guid>
      <description>  Election Data by State for the 2016 Presidential Elections
 Gun Violence Incidents in the United States in 2014
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>